<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IDL on</title><link>https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/</link><description>Recent content in IDL on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/introduction/</guid><description>REST APIs often include dependency constraints that restrict how two or more parameters can be combined to form valid API calls. These inter-parameter dependencies make it difficult to automatically interact with the services, since API specification languages offer little or no support for them. We carried out a study on 40 industrial APIs and found that 85% of them contain inter-parameter dependencies. More importantly, we classified all the dependencies found (over 600) into seven patterns, serving as the basis for future proposals for modeling and analyzing inter-parameter dependencies automatically.</description></item><item><title>How to use IDL</title><link>https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://isa-group.github.io/IDL/docs/idl/quick-start/</guid><description>IDL dependencies can be straightforwardly specified in OAS specifications using IDL4OAS, an OAS extension. You just need to include the keyword x-dependencies at the operation level, and include the list of dependencies as an array. Take a look at this simple example:
paths: /example/route: get: operationId: exampleOperation parameters: - in: query type: boolean required: false name: p1 - in: query type: integer required: false name: p2 - in: query type: string required: false name: p3 x-dependencies: - Or(p1, p2, p3); - IF p1==true THEN p2;</description></item></channel></rss>